Are you obedient?
你听话不
Are you?
听话不
You will be the captain then.
那你当队长
All right, let's get ready to go.
好 准备出发
My students.
同学们
From now on,
从今天起
you are on the same team.
你们就是一个队的队友了
When we get there later,
等一会到了地方
don't run around,
别乱跑
don't look elsewhere,
别乱看
and don't talk nonsense.
别乱说
Do you still remember our school motto?
咱们的校训你们都记得吧
These are the members of our team.
这就是我们队的全体成员
I'm Zhang Wei,
我叫张伟
one of the five students named "Zhang Wei" in Shaohai Third High School.
是绍海三中四个张伟中的一个
I'm the most ordinary one among them.
也是最普通的一个
I don't have many hobbies,
我的爱好不多
nor any particular goal.
也没什么特别的目标
My results are fine.
学习成绩 还行
I'm telling you. You are not fine.
我告诉你还不行
Students like you are the most troublesome.
最头疼的就是你这种学生
You are neither up nor down,
不上不下
neither good nor bad.
不好不坏
Do you think you can slack off as a junior?
高二不需要努力了
Let me tell you.
我告诉你 到了高三
It will be too late when you become a senior.
你哭你都来不及
In your case...
就你这种情况
I got 24 marks.
我二十四
Ququ is my best friend.
蛐蛐是我的死党
He is naturally hyperactive
天性好动
and simple minded.
没心没肺
Come. Come on.
来呀 来呀
Qu Xiaodong!
曲小东
Get up!
你给我站起来
You came in last in the class.
你考了全班倒数第一
What is there to be proud of?
你有什么得意的
Go and stand at the back.
都站后边去
In this exam...
这次考试呢
He always takes our self study class.
天天占自习
Don't you think Mr. Xia is crazy?
你说老夏是不是有病
If he didn't drag me
如果不是他
to join the school swimming team,
拉着我加入校游泳队
I might never have the courage
我可能永远也没有勇气
to escape from those annoying self study classes.
逃离那两节让人不爽的自习课
There's also Wang Zi who just transferred from the Northeast.
还有刚从东北转学过来的王子
Let me show you
让你们看看
what is "good looks sealed away by glasses."
什么是被眼镜封印的颜值
He has a dorky personality.
性格呆萌
Are you still recruiting members?
你们还缺人吗
He is someone
大概是我见过的
who loves to make friends.
最爱交朋友的人
Let me join you.
带我一个呗
Next is Chen Minghan of Class 1, a junior.
还有就是高二一班的陈铭涵
The overall top scorer is Chen Minghan again.
总分第一又是陈铭涵
He always ranked first in various subjects.
蝉联各种总分第一
Chen Minghan,I'm not asking about the subject.
陈铭涵 我问的不是课程科目
I'm asking about your hobby.
是兴趣爱好
I'm talking about my hobby.
我说的也是爱好
Trigonometric functions are my hobby.
我的爱好就是三角函数
He could be the "model child"
他可能就是我妈说的那种
my mom often talks about.
别人家的孩子吧
Gao Fei.
高飞
He is the best sports student at our school.
我们学校优质的体育特长生
Yet he refused to join any sports clubs.
却拒绝参加一切体育社团
In everyone's eyes,
在大家眼里
he looks cool and mysterious.
他一直很酷很神秘
It's on fire!
着火啦
What?
什么
Your shirt is on fire!
你的衣服着火啦
What happened?
怎么回事
Did you do this?
你干的
I?
我
There was a loose thread on your shirt.
衣服上有一个线头
Mr. Kui is our coach.
奎老师是我们的教练
He is passionate about his job.
工作负责 激情澎湃
He is overenthusiastic
平常干什么事儿
in all that he does.
都跟打了鸡血似的
You have to get me two swimmers from the team.
你还得从游泳队里面给我调俩人
During the High School Water Sports Meeting,
举办这次高中水上运动会
However, with too much enthusiasm,
可是鸡血打多了
it's easy
就容易
to be sleepy.
困
under the premise of ensuring the quality of learning.
提高高中生的全面素质
So we are hoping that
所以我们希望
each school will look at their own circumstances
各个学校根据自己的情况
and put together this men's?
组建这个男子
It's "women's."
是女子
No.
不对
It's a women's synchronized swimming team.
是女子花样游泳队
Of course.
当然了
If there is any school that would want to form a men's team,
哪个学校愿意多组建一支男子的
we would welcome it equally.
我们也一样欢迎
This has an innovative meaning to it.
这个 创新的意义
Instead of focusing on college entrance exams
就在于要和以前单纯注重升学率
What did the chief just say?
领导刚才说什么了
About forming a men's synchronized swimming team.
组建男子花样游泳队
The chief was just joking?
领导开玩笑说的
The other schools formed women's teams?
别的学校都是女队
It's just our school that formed a men's team?
就我们学校一个男队
I got it.
我知道了
Okay.
好
Okay, bye.
好 再见
How can you not even know the gender?
你怎么连性别都搞错了呢
The chief was joking.
领导开玩笑
Couldn't you tell?
听不出来吗
There's not a single men's synchronized swimming team
这全国也找不出一支
in this country that is complete.
完整的男子花样游泳队
If that's the case,
那您看
what should we do now?
现在怎么办
What else can we do?
还能怎么办
We have already submitted it.
都已经报上去了
You should recruit the members first.
你先把人招起来吧
Don't let the headmaster find out
别到时候校长问起来
that there are not enough members.
连人都没招齐呢
Okay.
好
How many have you recruited?
招几个了
Five.
五个
We already have five members.
已经招五个了
The five of you
你们五个
must show the good mental health
一定要展现出高中生
of high school students.
优良的精神面貌
Right.
对了
Welcome to the Men's Synchronized Swimming Team.
那个 欢迎加入男子花样游泳队
I'm in Class 2.
我二班的
My surname is Wang.
我姓王
I'm Wang Zi.
我叫王子
I'm in Class 7.
我七班的
My surname is "Father."
我姓父
I'm "King Father."
我叫父王
Isn't this a swimming team?
不是游泳队吗
How did it become synchronized swimming?
怎么变花样的了
Synchronized swimming
花样游泳
is also known as water ballet.
又有水上芭蕾之称
It originated in Europe.
起源于欧洲
It started
最早是在
as a performance
游泳比赛的间歇的时候
during the intervals of swimming competitions.
进行的一个表演项目
It is highly artistic
它具备很高的艺术性
and requires certain techniques,
需要一定的技巧
along with dancing and strength basics.
舞蹈和力量的基础
In general,
一般来说
synchronized swimming is divided into
花样游泳运动分为
solo,
单人
duet,
双人
mixed duet,
混双
and team categories.
和集体项目
Based on the Olympic standards and rules,
按照奥运会的标准和规则
it has to be eight people in a team.
集体项目的人数必须是八个人
She is talking to all of you.
这跟你们说话呢
Can you guys focus?
能不能认真听一下啊
Mr. Kui.
奎老师
I have other training plans.
我下面还有其他的训练安排
I'll get going.
我就先走了
I'm sorry.
不好意思啊
I'll leave you to it.
您忙
Sorry for the trouble.
添麻烦了
Mr. Kui.
奎老师
Do we have to do this too?
我们也要练这个
They are all girls.
她们都是女孩
What's wrong with girls?
女孩怎么了
If girls can learn boxing,
那女孩能练拳击
why can't boys learn synchronized swimming?
男孩就不能练花游吗
Look carefully.
好好看
Look at their movements.
看动作
Look at the formations.
看队形
Don't look away.
别看别的
It's unreliable.
不靠谱
What's wrong?
怎么了
A few boys doing synchronized swimming.
几个男的练花样游泳
Doesn't it feel strange?
你不觉得奇怪
Also, there are only five of us.
而且咱们就五个人
What about that?
五个人怎么了
How can the five of us slack off?
五个人怎么偷懒
Besides, Mr. Kui mentioned a competition.
而且奎大猛说还有比赛
We will have to train for real then.
那咱们到时候不得真练啊
What should we do?
那怎么办啊
Let's go to a soccer team.
要不去足球队吧
There are so many people.
那人多
Or a basketball team.
篮球队也行
There are dozens of them.
好几十个呢
Hey, guys.
来同学们
Class is starting.
来上课了
In this self study class,
这节自习课
let me share a way
让我们来分享一道
of problem solving at the Nobel Prize level.
诺贝尔级的解题思路
Come on.
来来来
Let's look at this hero.
让我们看看这个大侠
Let's see how did he get the piece of weight
他是怎么让重锤片
to fall.
下落的
Let's take a look.
我们来看一下
Click.
咔嚓
He cut it off
给我砍断了
with a Blood Drinking Blade.
用的是血饮狂刀
That's amazing.
厉害啊
Qu Xiaodong.
曲小东
Where is he?
人呢
Excuse me.
报告
Excuse me, sir.
不好意思老师
We have training today.
我们今天有训练
Hurry up, Zhang Wei.
快点张伟
The coach will scold us if we are late.
一会迟到又要被教练骂
Excuse me, Mr. Xia.
不好意思 夏老师
Mr. Xia, I'll see you tomorrow.
夏老师 明天见
Didn't you say you won't go?
不是说不去了吗
As long as we skip this class,
只要不上自习课
I'm fine with anything. Let's go.
练什么都行 走
This is great!
太爽了
Captain, jump in!
队长下来
Come on.
快来
What are you doing?
干吗呢
I went to the bathroom.
上厕所去了
What are you doing now?
我问你现在干吗呢
I'm sitting down.
坐着呀
Sitting down?
坐着
Did I ask you to come here to sit down?
我让你来是坐着来的是不
I'll pay for your clothes and wallet.
那我赔你衣服赔你钱包
Let me go.
你让我走
You! What are you doing as a captain?
那个谁 你怎么当的队长
Hurry up and gather at the starting point!
赶紧给我出发点集合
You two!
你们两个
Gather at the starting point!
出发点集合
Listen to me.
注意听我讲
You guys.
同学们
You must take this training seriously.
你们一定要重视这一次训练
This will become
这将成为你们人生中
a very memorable lesson in your life.
非常值得铭记的一课
You have to be brave.
你们要勇敢
You have to fight.
你们要拼搏
You have to be fearless.
你们要勇者无畏
Listen to my whistle.
听我的哨声
Once you hear it,
哨声响起之后
do your best
全力以赴
and sprint to the other side.
冲向对岸
Show me how outstanding you are.
让我看到你们优秀的素质
All right?
好不好
Get ready.
准备
Focus your energy.
集中精力
Ready.
预备
Call me if you need anything.
有什么事儿打电话啊
Headmaster.
校长
That's right.
对对对
He has been taken to the hospital.
人已经送医院去了
Xiaofu is with him.
小付跟着呢
I'll keep you posted.
有情况我向您汇报
Freedom!
自由啦
In my notes,
我那个笔记里面
there is your training plan.
有你们的训练计划
You have to understand it.
你一定要好好领会
Use it to lead the team and build the basics.
这个带着大家打打基础
Get in the mood.
找找感觉
When the coach is absent,
教练不在的时候
the captain is the coach.
队长就是教练
Do you understand?
明白吗
So as the captain,
所以你作为队长
you must take responsibility.
一定要负起责任来
Do you hear me?
听到没有
But I have never been a captain.
可我没当过队长
How should I take responsibility?
怎么负责任
I have to lead our training too.
我还要带着大家训练
How can we train?
怎么练啊
Zhang Wei!
张伟
Let's race.
咱俩比一圈
I'm busy.
我忙着呢
It's not right if you don't get into the pool.
不是你不下水不合适吧
Chen Minghan!
陈铭涵
Let's have a race.
咱俩来一局
Come.
来
Let's race again.
咱俩再比一把
You won't do.
你不行啊
Let's hold our breaths.
比憋气
The loser buys drinks.
输了的请喝饮料
Sure, let's do it.
行 来
You said it.
你说的啊
Won't you wish me good luck?
你不祝福我一下吗
Just stay alive.
活着就好
Ready.
预备
One, two, three.
一 二 三
Mom and Dad are busy tonight.
爸妈晚上有事
I have to study.
我有晚自习
Go home by yourself today.
你今天自己回家
Are they training?
他们在训练吗
I don't know.
不知道
Next time,make sure you have your keys with you.
下次记得自己带钥匙
Chen Minghan.
陈铭涵
Who is it?
谁啊
My elder sister.
我姐
You are good, kid.
可以啊 小伙
You sure have a firm butt.
小伙屁股挺有弹性嘛
Come on.
来啊来啊来啊
Why did you kick me?
踹我干嘛
To buy you a drink.
请你喝饮料啊
Come on.
来来来
Don't go.
别走
Buy me a drink.
给我买饮料
Are you blind?
眼瞎吧你
You are the one who is blind.
不是你才瞎呢
What are you doing?
你们干吗
We want to train.
我们训练
We are training today.
今天我们训练
You don't even have a coach.
你们连教练都没有
What are you doing in the pool?
占着泳池干什么呀
Hurry up and leave.
赶紧腾地儿
Kou Zi.
寇子
Talk to him nicely.
跟人好好说话
Hello.
同学你好
I'm the captain of the swimming team.
我是游泳队队长
Is your captain here?
你们队长在吗
What do you want?
你有事吗
I have something to discuss with him.
有点事跟他商量一下
You can talk to me.
你跟我说就行
Why can't you talk to me?
怎么不能说吗
What's wrong, Ququ?
怎么了蛐蛐
This is our captain.
这是我们队长
Say it then.
说呗
The thing is,
是这样的
we are entering a competition.
我们呢 要参加一个比赛
Right now,our training time is tight.
现在呢 训练时间比较紧张
You don't have a coach either.
我看你们也没有教练
Let us use the pool first.
这个泳池 就先给我们用吧
Okay?
好吧
Thank you.
谢谢了
Let's go and train.
走 训练
Why do you get the final say?
你说让就让啊
Or what?
不然呢
Should we leave it for you to learn synchronized swimming?
留给你们自学花样游泳啊
Shake your butt.
屁股扭一扭
Shake your upper body.
上身扭一扭
How sissy is that?
娘不娘啊
Stop right there!
给我站住
Do you want a one on one fight?
不是你是不是想单挑啊
Sure.
可以啊
Do you dare to have a swimming race?
挑游泳敢吗
Yes.
敢啊
The loser will have to leave.
谁输谁走人
The loser has to get lost.
谁输谁滚蛋
Come on.
来啊
Zhang Wei!
张伟
Do it!
上
Don't give me that.
啊什么啊
You are the captain.
你是队长
Destroy him.
灭他
Kou Zi.
寇子
Leave them alone.
别欺负他们
Xiaochong.
小虫
You should go.
你上
You can do it, Captain!
你可以的队长
Come on,
加油
That's more than enough.
气势已经很足了
Ready.
预备
Come on!
加油
Captain!Come on!
队长 加油
Hurry up, Zhang Wei!
快点 张伟
What's wrong, Zhang Wei?
怎么了 张伟
Why did you climb up there?
怎么爬上去了
What's happening?
什么情况
What's wrong with you, Zhang Wei?
你什么情况张伟
He has a cramp!
抽筋啦
You can't do it, can you?
不行了呗
Who can't do it?
不是谁不行
He can't do it.
他不行
Can you do it?
不是你行吗
I can do it.
我行啊
Do you dare to compete with us?
那咱俩来啊
Come on.
你来啊
Come on! Let's go!
来啊来啊 上
Anyone of you.
随便上一个人
Come on!
快点
Ready.
准备
Aren't you being unreasonable?
赖不赖啊
Let's go.
走
Captain of the swimming team,
游泳队队长
let's race.
咱俩比一局吧
What?
什么
Let's race.
咱俩比一局
Excuse me.
同学
This is going on forever.
这么比下去没完没了啊
Choose between 100 and 200 m.
一百米还是两百米你选
All right.
行吧
200 m.
两百
You really have to leave if you lose this time.
这回输了可真得走人了啊
On your mark.
各就各位
Get set.
预备
Go for it!
加油
Gao Fei,Go for it!
高飞 加油
Gao Fei! We're leading!
高飞 领先了
That's incredible!
厉害 厉害
Stay strong, Gao Fei!
别虚啊 高飞
Stay strong,
别虚
The captain is overtaking you.
队长反超了
Nicely done!
漂亮
Rise powerfully!
雄起
Soar to the top!
往上顶
Steady,
稳住啊
Soar to the top, Gao Fei!
往上顶 高飞
Gao Fei! Go for it, Gao Fei!
高飞 加油 高飞
Come forward, Gao Fei!
冲啊 往前来 高飞
Sprint forward!
往前冲
Keep steady!
稳住稳住
That's amazing.
太帅了
That's amazing, Gao Fei!
太厉害了 高飞
That's awesome!
牛啊
Is there anyone else who wants a race?
还有谁要比吗
Then don't just stand there.
那就别愣着了
Let's go.
走
You are leaving?
走啦
It's okay.
没事
That was great.
很棒了
Keep it up.
继续加油
Let's race again next time.
我们下次再比
Good luck.
加油
Gao Fei, you are amazing!
高飞 太帅了
Teach me how to swim.
教我游泳吧
Have you trained before?
你以前是不是练过
Can you teach me?
你教我游呗 行吗
I'll buy you a drink.
我请你喝饮料
You can choose any drink.
你想喝什么喝什么
Gao Fei. Is that all right?
高飞 行不行
I'll take your silence as a yes.
你不说话就是答应了啊
Master.
师父
He is amazing!
太帅了
A captain
队长
should be someone like him.
应该是他这样的吧
They want to rob our territory?
还抢地盘
Go against them.
反了他们了
We won't give in to anyone.
谁来咱们都不让
Our synchronized swimming team
咱们花游队
must not panic and must stay together.
一不能乱 二不能散
You are the captain.
你作为队长
No matter what happens,
无论什么压力
you have to hang in there.
你一定给我顶住
You must know.
你们一定要知道
This will become
这一课将成为你们人生中
a very memorable lesson in your life.
非常值得铭记的一课
So you should cherish it,
所以你们要珍惜
fight on,
要拼搏
and?
要
Miss!
护士
Mr. Kui.
奎老师
Hello?
喂